<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal Opinions on Skand Hurkat – Computer Systems Lab, Cornell University</title>
    <link>http://skandhurkat.github.io/tags/personal-opinions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal Opinions on Skand Hurkat – Computer Systems Lab, Cornell University</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 09:04:44 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/personal-opinions/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Neutrality</title>
      <link>http://skandhurkat.github.io/post/net-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 09:04:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://skandhurkat.github.io/post/net-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, my website displays a banner to join the fight for an open
internet. My message to the FCC follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FCC&amp;rsquo;s Open Internet Rules (net neutrality rules) are extremely
important to me. I urge you to protect them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a person who is not an American citizen, I was led to believe
(perhaps wrongly) that America as a capitalist society would value the
very principles that allow a free market to function, namely a free flow
of information and healthy competition. It seems that I was mistaken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposed changes to the FCC rules negatively impact both these
principles. The internet is the epitome of a free flow of information,
however misunderstood it may be amongst those who make laws. A free and
open internet is one where all data is treated equal, and ISPs and cable
companies cannot distinguish between any kind of traffic. They should
not be allowed to create fast lanes or zero-rate some form of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creation of fast lanes or zero-rating some traffic while charging
for other forms of traffic goes against the spirit of free competition
in the market. It means that no one could create the next Google or
NetFlix unless they can get ISPs on board with their plan and provide
their traffic with the same high speed or low cost. It means that ISPs
will have ultimate control, not just of their own market (which, as I
shall discuss next is a monopoly), but also of other markets far removed
from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, almost everything runs on networked computers. Any system that
must work across the width of a continent, or across multiple cities
uses the internet in some way or the other to communicate information
across. Even our phone lines are now increasingly routed over the
internet, using VoIP technology. Our light bulbs and toaster ovens will
soon use the internet as IoT becomes ubiquitous. So, support for net
neutrality is not just a fight for the internet; absence of net
neutrality and putting ISPs in position as gatekeeper would harm not
just internet services, but could extend to the physical world as well,
as the gap between physical and virtual worlds gets shorter and shorter.
We must ask: what gives ISPs the right to decide what works and what
doesn&amp;rsquo;t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sooner lawmakers realise this fundamental truth, the better. &lt;strong&gt;ISPs
do not own the internet. They have not created the infrastructure for
the internet. They have done nothing other than create a monopoly that
taxes people to access a technology that was the product of taxpayer
dollars and DARPA research.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, ISPs are a monopoly in the USA. Right now, if I want internet
access, I have only one option, Time Warner, now called Spectrum. If I
lived in Pittsburgh, I would have only one option, Comcast. Monopolies
are antithetical to the free market. But I don&amp;rsquo;t need to tell you that.
A capitalist society should balk at the very idea of a monopoly. Yet,
lawmakers seem to accept and deny the very existence of these monopolies
in almost all facets of American life, rather than fulfil their role as
regulators and regulate the industries with monopolies to serve the very
people who elect them into office and not the industry lobbyists who pay
them money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If my country &amp;ndash; India &amp;ndash; could enact strong net neutrality
protections at a point in its history when ubiquitous internet access
was (and is) still not widespread throughout the country, I&amp;rsquo;m surprised
that the country that gave the world the free internet is now so eager
to destroy it to serve the interests of a small group of cable companies
that had nothing to do with the creation of the internet, and through
sheer coincidence ended up controlling everyone&amp;rsquo;s access to taxpayer
funded technology.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cornell Graduate Students United: At what cost?</title>
      <link>http://skandhurkat.github.io/post/cgsu-at-what-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 17:56:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://skandhurkat.github.io/post/cgsu-at-what-cost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday and Tuesday, we graduate students at Cornell will be voting on
whether or not we want to unionise. Actually, scratch that, only
graduate students who hold a TA, RA, or GRA appointment can unionise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a shitty arrangement, and I will be voting against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are not aware of how graduate school works at
Cornell, you could be on one of many appointments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Fellowship&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;A graduate student on a fellowship gets a stipend and tuition paid
without associated teaching or research opportunities. Graduate students
on a fellowship typically work towards their own theses, but will be
excluded from the union&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Graduate research assistantships&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;A GRA gives a graduate student stipend and tuition without teaching
responsibilities. However, this money comes out of a specific project
grant, and the students typically work on their own theses. Students on
GRAs magically qualify to join the union, whereas there is virtually no
difference between a GRA and a fellowship for the most part.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Research assistantships&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;An RA appointment provides stipend and tuition without teaching
responsibilities, but with research responsibilities. Students on an RA
appointment must work on projects that may not be their own theses. RAs
qualify to form a union&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Teaching assistantships&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;A TA appointment provides stipend and tuition with teaching
responsibilities. TA appointments qualify to form a union.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This breakdown shows that the union organisation is already on tenuous
ground, as students could move in and out of these various appointments
on a semester-by-semester basis. Receiving and losing union protection
every four months is like not receiving any protection at all. If the
union truly believes that students are exploited by professors (which I
must categorically state, I am not. I love my job, I love my lab, and I
love my advisor), then they are leaving a gaping loophole wherein a
professor could simply move a student out of one of the protected
appointments to an unprotected appointment, then crap all over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not the primary reason I am opposed to the union. &lt;strong&gt;At every
stage in campaigning for our votes, the union has been shifty and
deceitful&lt;/strong&gt;, sometimes resorting to outright lies that could be easily
disproved. For instance, the union always brought up a case of a student
in the department of chemical engineering who lost his appointment at a
lab following an accident that allegedly left him unable to control his
right hand for a couple of years. The union&amp;rsquo;s position was, well, if
only there were a union to fight for workers&amp;rsquo; compensation, that student
would still be at Cornell. Here&amp;rsquo;s the lie &amp;ndash; &lt;strong&gt;students on a GRA, RA, or
TA are already protected by workers&amp;rsquo; compensation&lt;/strong&gt;. That particular
student was on a fellowship, and this underscores my point about the
shittiness of students receiving different protections for the same work
based on an arbitrary status. In this student&amp;rsquo;s case, the union would
have simply walked away with a &amp;lsquo;Not my problem&amp;rsquo; statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I am a fan of collective bargaining. I believe that we students may
still get a lot done through collective bargaining, but the union in its
current form is not the way to do so. For starters, the union will not
cover all graduate students, and I abhor the idea of leaving some fellow
students in virtually the same position as myself without the
protections of collective bargaining simply based on a technicality. But
this is ignoring the fact that Cornell has an organisation that could
achieve collective bargaining for graduate students, the Graduate and
Professional Students Assembly (GPSA), which has successfully managed to
achieve many things in Cornell, such as negotiating our wages to be
raised at 2% a year, above the current inflation rate of 1%. The last
president, Elizabeth Garrett also increased graduate student salaries
across the board, making RA and GRA salaries the same as TA salaries.
Now, asking us to put $500&amp;ndash;1000 towards union dues is stupid,
considering that we make $30,000 a year before state and federal income
taxes. What&amp;rsquo;s also crazy is that the union apparently will have a
two-tiered structure, wherein we may be expected to pay more in order to
have a vote (a voice) in the union. This is taxation without
representation, and I will always vote against such an arrangement on a
matter of principle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the union seems like a power grab by a bunch of sloppy
students. The entire process was undemocratic to say the least, and
seemed just like a page out of Catch-22. Sign the union authorisation
card. Well, what am I signing up for? Come to our meetings and find out.
Cool, how do I do that? You must sign the card to come to our meetings.
The process was secret, with no voice from graduate students who may
have been on the fence, and with further amendments to artificially
inflate the voices of some students. Take, for instance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cornellgsu.org/s/CGSUNegotiatingCommitteeConstitutionalAmendment.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this
amendment&lt;/a&gt;,
which grants equal voice on the negotiating committee to students from
the six jurisdictions, whereas the number of students in these
jurisdictions are by no means the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, some of the provisions on the Cornell GSU constitution defy
logic, and show that they were probably written by monkeys on
typewriters. See, for instance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cornellgsu.org/our-constitution/#IV.A.A2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Section
IV.A.A2&lt;/a&gt;, which states
that any grievance against any member of the union will be shared across
all members of the union. I do not see this as helpful. While
transparency is good, it should be balanced with privacy. Publishing a
list of grievances without verification of the claims is irresponsible,
and promotes a lynch-mob mentality which will make the environment at
Cornell a lot more hostile and toxic. I realise that I am not providing
evidence to support this claim &amp;ndash; the fact is that I am basing this off
an existing incident which I do not wish to publicise, firstly, because
I heard this account second-hand, and in order to protect the privacy of
the persons that may have been involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the process of getting rid of a dysfunctional union will be
much, much harder than the process of voting one in. So, to my friends
who say that they want to &amp;lsquo;try it out&amp;rsquo;, let me remind them that this is
the equivalent of &amp;lsquo;trying out&amp;rsquo; arson. You will probably get burned, and
you&amp;rsquo;ll be leaving a whole future generation of graduate students with a
mess that they&amp;rsquo;ll have to deal with for the entirety of their graduate
student life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, the union in its current form is a juvenile power grab
without a stated objective, a mission, or a plan to achieve its
objectives. Voting for the union is the equivalent of voting for Donald
Trump, and I hope that my friends can now see how that&amp;rsquo;s working out for
the USA. Do not, do not vote for the union. Vote against it, let them
come up with something better instead of an empty promise for something
better. We can always vote for a better union next year. But we cannot
vote out a shitty union once it&amp;rsquo;s formed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A history of computing -- my perspective</title>
      <link>http://skandhurkat.github.io/post/history-of-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 17:46:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://skandhurkat.github.io/post/history-of-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because I can publish shitty drawings, and even shittier text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I have no obligation to be accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;04.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;06.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;07.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;08.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;09.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;11.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;12.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;13.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;14.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
