<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Skand Hurkat – Computer Systems Lab, Cornell University</title>
    <link>http://skandhurkat.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Skand Hurkat – Computer Systems Lab, Cornell University</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 15:52:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/machine-learning/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>EmoDetect</title>
      <link>http://skandhurkat.github.io/project/emodetect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 15:52:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://skandhurkat.github.io/project/emodetect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We developed EmoDetect, an open source system for identifying human
emotion from images. This system has an accuracy of around 63% in
identifying the correct emotion from amongst seven candidates. Our
experiments showed that humans did slightly better, with an accuracy of
74%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was aimed as a comparative study of different feature
extractors and learning algorithm combinations for the task of
identifying emotion from static images. Our study revealed that Gabor
features with a linear, soft margin SVM performed best.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CarDetect</title>
      <link>http://skandhurkat.github.io/project/cardetect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 16:37:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://skandhurkat.github.io/project/cardetect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CarDetect is a system to identify car numberplates (registration plates)
and car make and model. This system was supposed to help law enforcement
officials identify fake numberplates and stolen cars. I worked on this
project for over a year and achieved over 98% accuracy in recognizing
numberplate regions, and over 90% accuracy in recognizing car models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was implemented in OpenCV using C/C++. The code for the
project can be found on my GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that I&amp;rsquo;m no longer working on CarDetect. The code on my
GitHub repository has not been changed since 2011, with the exception of
adding a build system using CMake. I&amp;rsquo;ve also modified the code to use
C++11 features; including the multithreaded model, but performance is
not as good as the original Windows code, found in the Woe32 branch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text-independent speaker verification</title>
      <link>http://skandhurkat.github.io/project/text-independent-speaker-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2010 17:09:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://skandhurkat.github.io/project/text-independent-speaker-verification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We developed a system to identify users independent of their spoken
words. The system used Mel-frequency cepstral coefficients (MFCCs) to
obtain a characteristic pattern of the user&amp;rsquo;s voice which was then
analysed by a three layer multi-layer perceptron (MLP) neural network.
We obtained accuracies of over 90% using this approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire project was implemented in MATLAB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
