<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Isca on Skand Hurkat</title>
    <link>https://skandhurkat.com/tags/isca/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Isca on Skand Hurkat</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Skand Hurkat. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 17:28:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://skandhurkat.com/tags/isca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on ISCA 2017</title>
      <link>https://skandhurkat.com/post/thoughts-isca-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 17:28:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skandhurkat.com/post/thoughts-isca-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m back from the 44&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; International Symposium on Computer
Architecture, and this is a perfect time for me to summarise my thoughts
on the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference was in Toronto, which was a refreshing change for me to
see correct spelling and sensible units for a change. Beyond that, the
conference had a lot of interesting developments, and some that were not
quite as interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let me address the 15-month elephant in the room. That&amp;rsquo;s Google&amp;rsquo;s
Tensor processing unit (TPU) paper. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t impressed with the paper
(although I am impressed by the engineering), although a lot of people
seemed to be impressed by that paper. Indeed, only one other person I
spoke with at the conference seemed to share my views on the matter. My
criticism of the TPU paper is that it really gives little information.
An application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC) will obviously have
much less power/energy and much higher performance over a general
purpose processor. The really interesting parts of the TPU would have
been the Tensorflow-to-control-instructions compiler and driver.
Unfortunately, these details still remain elusive. In fact, the whole
paper describes (or fails to describe) technology that is over four
years old and has already been replaced. In my opinion, I find more
information in Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Project
Zero&lt;/a&gt; blog than I did in the
TPU paper and the associated talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the next bit. ISCA had a &amp;lsquo;Trends in Machine Learning&amp;rsquo;
workshop, which I found as, if not more interesting than the main
conference. There were some really cool demos, such as real-time neural
networks running on embedded devices such as an iPhone and a Raspberry
Pi, &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://clinc.com/&#34;&gt;Clinc&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;,
which can process natural speech and respond to queries on your
finances, DeepSpeech by Baidu, amongst others. The trend towards machine
learning was apparent even through the main program, with multiple
papers on accelerating neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like any other conference, there were also some presentations that
had me completely zoned out. There were some that felt just like a
rehash of old ideas, and some which left me scratching my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overarching theme of the keynotes and the panel discussion, however,
were on the inevitable end of Moore&amp;rsquo;s law, with Mark Bohr from Intel
claiming that the law was merely tired and shagged out after a long
squawk, with plots showing that the number of transistors are indeed
doubling as expected from Moore&amp;rsquo;s law. Partha Ranganathan from Google,
on the other hand pointed out that the law had joined the choir
invisible. Partha argued that this was indeed a fun time to be an
architect, to talk to those annoying people working with software to
co-design hardware and software with the point of unlocking more
potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, if there is one message that I would take away from the
conference, it is that we computer architects have to fundamentally
change the way we look at our job. For years, computer architects were
perfectly happy using the extra transistors that the devices folks gave
us to make faster computers, and the evil people working in software
would take away this performance through even more bloated software.
Now, the pipeline has dried up, the devices people are not able to give
us faster and smaller transistors, and they definitely cannot give us
more power-efficient transistors because Dennard scaling is almost
certainly dead. As a result, we architects have to find ways to use
these transistors more efficiently. This means talking to the software
gremlins, understanding their evil algorithms and implementing them in
beautiful silicon. The future is almost certainly in going green by
reducing our power requirements and in grudgingly enabling the software
people to unlock greater functionality, not by relying on faster
computers, but by relying on custom, bespoke hardware that can run their
algorithms in an efficient manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How such bespoke hardware should be deployed remains a challenge. We can
almost certainly not sell chips for mobile phones with the area of a
football field with billions of custom accelerators that are almost
always turned off except for a few running a custom app. My opinion is
that the best way to deploy these accelerators in the present moment is
in datacentres, to provide them to users as a service. Google is already
making great headway by allowing people to &lt;em&gt;rent&lt;/em&gt; cloud machines with
TPUs (I still dislike the TPU paper &amp;#x1f604;) and to use TensorFlow to
accelerate their workloads. I could envision cloud providers allowing
people to time-multiplex multiple accelerators in some sort of
mutual-fund or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.massdrop.com/&#34;&gt;Massdrop&lt;/a&gt; like cloud service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe the future is in taking a step back and rethink our obsession
with Von Neumann machines with variants of the five-stage pipeline and
redraw our computers from scratch. I think it&amp;rsquo;s an exciting time to be
an architect, and also scary. As a PhD candidate, I have to try really
hard to look at the exciting bits and not the scary ones. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
